# Sheila H.Y. Yuan

301-873-8752 | shyyuan@yahoo.com

#### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with over 18 years of experience in both front-end application and back end database development; having years of experience in working across the full System Development Live Cycle (SDLC). Expertise in relational databases and PL/SQL programming. Will complete a 13-weeks training in June 2017 with updated Web Development skills such as HTML5, CSS Framework, and MEAN stack development.

### SUMMARY OF SKILLS

Database and Tools: Oracle Database (7.x/8/8i/9i/10g/11g/12c), Toad, SQL\*Plus, SQL Developer, SQL

Loader, SQL Server 2000, Access VBA, Mongo DB, PostgreSQL

Application/Programming: WebFOCUS, Cold Fusion, PL/SQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Python, PHP, JSP

#### **TRAINING**

BAH Sponsored Full-Time Training in General Assembly Web Development Immersive Program

Mar 2017 - Jun 2017

- HTML5, JavaScript, CSS with framework, and jQuery front end web development.
- Full stack application with RESTful routes using Mongo DB, Mongoose, Express, EJS, and Node.js.
- MEAN stack API development using Mongo DB, Express, AngularJS, and Node.js.
- Ruby on Rails server side development with AngularJS front end and PostgreSQL back end development.

## WORK EXPERIENCES

## Software Engineer, Booz Allen Hamilton Inc.

November 1998 – Present

Transportation Command (TRANSCOM) Regulating and Command & Control Evacuation System (TRAC<sup>2</sup>ES)

Sep 2016 – Feb 2017

- Modified existing WebFOCUS reporting objects and ad-hoc reports for TRAC2ES Organizational Data Store (TODS) based on clients' requirements for scheduled release.
- Modified database views and packages to implement the scheduled release.
- Participated in Oracle 12c upgrade by installing/upgrading software on development servers.

Transportation Command (TRANSCOM) Regulating and Command & Control Evacuation System (TRAC<sup>2</sup>ES)

Jan 2016 – May 2016

- Created new WebFOCUS reporting objects and reports for TRAC2ES Aeromedical Evacuation Registry (AER) Data Research Support task based on client's requirements.
- Created new Oracle database views and modified existing views to retrieve data for AER reports.
- Created database model and entity relationship diagram in supporting required documents for AER.

Online Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) Development and Implementation for Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) of the U.S. Department of Transportation, on-site at DoT Headquarter

Oct 2014 - Apr 2016

- Created and maintained database objects, such as tables, views, indexes, sequences, triggers, packages, and procedures for efficient data access and data integrity.
- Analyzed the data structures of the CFR XML files and the Federal Register Publication XML files which are from the Federal Digital System (FDsys) of the U.S. Government Publishing Office (GPO).
- Created and modified database procedures using XQuery to extract CFR, Appendixes, Hazmat Tables, and Rulemakings data from the XML files and load into Oracle database.
- Imported Interpretation Letters and Petitions records from Excel files to Oracle database.
- Created and modified database procedures to build relationships between CFR section and other modules, such as Rulemaking, Interpretation Letters, Outreach and Training Materials, and Petitions.

Sheila H.Y. Yuan
Page 1 of 3
May 2017

- Created and modified database packages and procedures to serve as Search function in CFR, Appendixes, Hazmat Tables, and Interpretation Letters modules. The procedures will return records set to display in front-end based on the passed in search criteria.
- Worked with developers to integrate the front-end and database design for the system. Helped developers with database query statements. Conducted system testing and provided feedback to developers.
- Composed database dictionary document and contributed in CONOPS document regarding data extracting steps.

U.S. Fleet Cyber Command Accreditation Tracker Database Application Aug 2014 – Sep 2014

Enhanced the U.S. Fleet Cyber Command Certification and Accreditation Tracker Application in Microsoft Access Database by modifying Access VBA codes to correct existing errors, add new functions, and create a new report in the system.

Transportation Command (TRANSCOM) Regulating and Command & Control Evacuation System (TRAC<sup>2</sup>ES) May 2005 – Jul 2014

- Created WebFOCUS reporting objects and ad-hoc reports for TRAC2ES Organizational Data Store (TODS) task. Successfully converted existing reports from Silverstream to WebFOCUS.
- Created and modified database views and packages that support TODS WebFOCUS reports.
- Assisted Oracle DBA in Oracle patches and 11g upgrade tasks.
- Performed database development for the Contractor Logistics Support (CLS) task in writing Database Design Document (DBDD) and SQL scripts, and modifying database procedures and packages.
- Participated in TRAC2ES web system development using Java (J2EE) and JSP to support several web application system releases.
- Maintained and supported the TRAC<sup>2</sup>ES WebWorks system using Cold Fusion and SQL Server.

Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) Recommendations Web Application System for the United States Marine Corps (USMC) Headquarter Jun 2006 - Sep2006

- Provided a short-term support in Phase I design and development while the developer was on leave.
- Performed as an Oracle DBA in database modeling, design and development for the system.
- Responsible for design, development, testing and implementation of the web-enabled database application using Cold Fusion, JavaScript and HTML.
- Completed Phase I within two months and successfully handed over to the original developer.

Facilities Integration (FI) Web Application System for the United States Marine Corps (USMC) Headquarter Nov 1999 – Apr 2005

- Performed as a technical lead in the USMC FI web application development team. The application was used by authorized Marine Corps facilities personnel in the execution of their local facilities program.
- Responsible for design, development, testing and implementation of the web-enabled database application tasks using Cold Fusion, JavaScript and HTML.
- Analyzed the existing system for enhancement that requested by clients.
- Experienced full life cycle software development. Involved in requirements, design, development, prototype, testing, documentation, implementation, and training phrases.
- Performed as an Oracle DBA to manage database objects and maintain data integrity.
- Responsible for monthly data updating by using Oracle script and export/import utilities to download data from Internet Navy Facility Assets Data Store (iNFADS) to FI database.
- Participated in the data transferring task between FI and Potomac Hudson Engineer Inc. (PHE) using Cold Fusion script and scheduler, and Oracle SQL Loader script. Provided data dump to PHE for any data discrepancy.
- Monitored daily scheduled tasks on Cold Fusion server.
- Installed Oracle database on the development and test servers under supervision of an Oracle DBA.
- Assisted in database design, Cold Fusion application developing for the Facilities Applications Management System (FAMS) and the Modification Request System (MRS) tasks in FI.
- Took charge of the GEOFidelis Inventory Website task in FI project, including requirement analysis, webpage and administration tool design, and database setup.

Interim Career Mobility Program (CMP) System for Recruiting Service Team in Global Operations (GO) Team of BAH Nov 1999 - Oct 2011

Sheila H.Y. Yuan Page 2 of 3

- Performed as the single person developer and database administrator on the project.
- Analyzed, implemented and maintained the Cold Fusion web-based application system and the Oracle database.
- Performed full life cycle enhancement at least once each year. Communicated with clients in identifying requirements and providing recommendations for implementation.
- Provided users with day-to-day support by being responsive to impromptu tasks and running ad-hoc reports.
- Modified and extended the system by adding functionalities requested by users. Improved the system with several
  enrichment releases by analyzing past ad hoc requests from users. The enhancements compensated the lack of
  functions in existing system and reduce users' unplanned requests.
- Collaborated with Information Service Team who hosted the system for system and database migration and upgrading releases.

Technical Information Resource Management (IRM) Support for the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs (OASD/PA), on-site at the Pentagon

May 1999 – Oct 1999

- Designed, developed, tested, prototyped and implemented the Briefing Room Reservation web application for the Directorate for Defense Information (DDI) in OASD/PA Intranet using Cold Fusion.
- Applied the interface to the existing database objects on Oracle server as backend processor.
- Maintained and modified existing Oracle applications in Forms 5.0 and Reports 3.0
- Executed basic Oracle DBA functions, created additional objects if necessary and managed all the objects in the database.
- Worked as a team member of technical IRM support in OASD/PA, provided general customer service and help desk support on Oracle and software issues.
- Assisted in workstation upgrade on clients' workstation. Assisted in installation and general setup of an Oracle client.

Information Technology Migration Plan for the Directorate for Freedom of Information and Security Review (DFOISR), on-site at the Pentagon

Nov 1998 – Apr 1999

- Customized format changes in Oracle Forms 5.0 and Reports 3.0 applications to meet DFOISR requirements for system migration.
- Implemented additional Forms and Reports applications enhancement requested by users.
- Completed all the tasks that were required in the contract and four out of eight tasks that were recommended but not required in the contract in less than four months.

## Oracle Developer, Biztrans Information Technologies Inc.

**August 1997 – October 1998** 

- Participated in full life cycle of an Oracle Developer2000 application project to create and maintain Customer Billing and Contact Management System.
- Created and managed database objects in Oracle database server, constructed dynamic scripts to generate SQL programs and used PL/SQL to create/modified database functions, procedures and packages to improve performance.
- Refreshed database data using SQL\*Loader, export and import to populate data.
- Designed, created, tested and modified Oracle Forms4.5 and Reports2.5 applications based on business rules and user's requirements.

**EDUCATION** 

M.S., Business Management, W. Averell Harriman School for Management and Policy, State University of New York at Stony Brook, Stony Brook, New York

B.S. Psychology, National Cheng-Chi University, Taipei, Taiwan

**AWARDS** BAH High 5 Award in 2012

BAH Performance and Team Award in 2008 and 2016

BAH Certificate of Appreciation Award for Outstanding Performance and Dedicated Service in

2000, 2002, 2004, 2006, and 2007

PERSONAL US Citizen